# William Hubenschmidt

whubenschmidt@gmail.com

mobile: 347-909-0064

https://hubenschmidt.github.io

# ABOUT ME

Full-stack developer with strong communications skills, creative background, and experience in database design, implementation, and management. Ten years experience in sales and fundraising roles. Specialties include JavaScript, Node/Express, React, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, Github, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Sequelize, Salesforce, event management, and proposal writing.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Full-Stack Developer, Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp, New York, NY

■ A 26-week immersive course in full-stack software development. Build, test and deploy full-stack applications. Collaborate on group projects and develop a strong foundational knowledge in MERN stack.

# 99¢ Dreams Records, 99¢ Radio, New York, NY

# Executive Producer & Audio Engineer, August 2010-present

- Audio production; imagine and execute sound design; lead projects from development to execution; specialize in vinyl record and cassette production and dance music sales reaching international audiences in Europe and Japan, achieving airplay on BBC Radio 1 Essential Mix.
- Live stream internet radio and digital content management including design and code of www.99centradio.com;
   HD video encoding and high quality audio streaming; social media and streaming audio service integration
- Event production; booking, promoting, and executing local events featuring house and electronic music artists.

# Nonprofit Fundraising Technology, New York, NY

# Consultant, January 2013-March 2016

- CRM database, web development, and fundraising for small business and mid-sized nonprofit clients including the Correctional Association of New York, Japan Society, James & Company, Color + Information, and Creative Connections, LLC.
- Co-authored "Why Every Nonprofit Needs CRM and How to Get it Right", a paper on best practices in database management and implementation in the nonprofit sector, published by Salsa (www.salsalabs.com).

## Amnesty International USA, New York, NY

## **Development Associate—Office of the Executive Director**, June 2012-January 2013

 Developed strategy to cultivate the organization's largest donors, wrote executive correspondence, managed donor database.

# Robert F. Kennedy Center for Justice and Human Rights, New York, NY

## Database Administrator, May 2011-June 2012

- Database management: implemented and managed Salesforce.com database for three international offices.
- Co-launched RFK Young Leaders, a young professionals' network to empower human rights activists and defenders; managed outreach, volunteer, and fundraising activities. Managed event productions featuring Q-Tip (2012) and Questlove (2013) to raise more than \$100,000 for human rights education project.

AmeriCorps VISTA, Austin, TX and New York, NY
Grant Writer and Database Analyst, April 2009-May 2011

#### **EDUCATION**

**Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp,** Columbia University, New York, NY, 2019 – Full Stack Web Development **University of Michigan**, Ann Arbor, MI, 2008 – B.A., American Culture/Music